# VAISHALI **YADAV**

MORADABAD, INDIA 244001 | 9871108602 | vaishaliyadav2086@gmail.com

**WWW:** Bold Profile

#### **SUMMARY**

Analytical Legal Researcher known for high productivity and efficiency in task completion. Specialised skills include legal analysis, case law research, and document drafting. Possess strong analytical thinking, problem-solving, and communication abilities that excel in interpreting complex legal documents and presenting findings.

# **SKILLS**

- Case Preparation
- Negotiation
- Time Management
- Legal counseling
- Legal knowledge
- Client Representation
- Document filing
- Document Review

- Research proficiency
- Crisis support
- Legal Research
- Mediation
- Conflict Resolution
- Legal Brief Preparation
- Legal writing
- Criminal Law

## **EXPERIENCE**

05/2023 - Current

# **Practicing Advocate**

**District and Sessions Court** - Moradabad

- Assists clients in understanding their legal rights and responsibilities.
- Provide advice to clients regarding their options for resolving disputes or legal issues.
- Conduct research into applicable laws, regulations, and precedents.

05/2021 - 08/2021

# Intern

#### Advocate Harshman Chavan

- Company Overview: Advocate, Bombay High Court
- Content Writing
- Research and writing articles on topics provided, etc.
- Areas of Law Covered: Criminal, Civil, Property, Family Laws, Divorce, Corporate, Cyber, and IT Crime, etc.

06/2021 - 06/2021

#### Intern

## Delhi State Legal Aid Services Authority

- Company Overview: Summer Internship Program
- Attending online sessions organised by the Authority on regular basis
- Preparing a project report titled as 'Outreach Program during COVID'
- Getting Google forms Questionnaire Filled from 30 community persons residing in Delhi only through telephonic Communication
- Summer Internship Program

05/2021 - 05/2021

Intern

Law Bhoomi

- Company Overview: Website
- Research and Writing on the topic provided

Website

02/2021 - 03/2021 Intern

Mr. Rohit Pandey

- Company Overview: Advocate on Record, Supreme Court
- Legal Research
- Studying Cases provided and preparing case briefs

• Advocate on Record, Supreme Court

01/2021 - 02/2021 Intern

Adhayayan Foundation of Policy and Research

- Research on topics provided
- Volunteering for events

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

01/2023 Maters in Law (LLM): Constitutional and Administrative Laws

Gujarat National Law University - Gandhinagar

GPA: 64%

01/2022 Bachelors in Law (LL.B.)

Campus Law Centre, Faculty of Law, University of Delhi

GPA: 63.6%

12/2019 Online Certificate Course: Forensic Psychology

Open University - United Kingdom

GPA: 82%

**01/2018 B.Sc.(H)**: Mathematics

P.G.DAV College, University of Delhi

GPA: 63.42%

01/2015 12th Standard

Spring fields School - Moradabad

GPA: 87.25%

01/2013 10th Standard

Spring fields School - Moradabad

GPA: 84%

# WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

• vaishali-yadav-b757101bb

#### ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

- Certified to Course on Computer Concepts (CCC), 03/2015, National Institute of Electronics and Information (NIELIT), Government of India
- Qualified UGC-NET, 06/2023
- Certified Online Legal Researcher, 01/2024, Manupatra

## **PUBLICATIONS**

• Empowering Choice: The Battle For Reproductive Freedom And A

- Woman's Right To Terminate Pregnancy, Indian Journal of Law and Legal Research, 09/25/23
- Resonating Justice: Audi Alteram Partem Unveiling Its Philosophy, Exceptions, And Legal Significance, White Black Legal International Law, 10/04/23
- Clashing Sovereignties: Unravelling The Doctrine Of Repugnancy In The Indian Federal System, International Journal for Legal Research and Analysis, 11/10/23
- From Chaos to Control: The Riveting Evolution of Political Party Regulations, Jus Corpus Law Journal, 06/10/24
- The Power Of Legitimate Expectation: Unveiling Rights, Limits, And Critiques, Journal of Law, University Institute of Laws, Panjab University Regional Centre, Ludhiana, 09/01/24

## **ARTICLES**

- Admission in Indian Evidence Act, LawBhoomi.com, 05/16/21
- Laws with E-Commerce in India, LawBhoomi.com, 05/25/21
- Directive Principles- Legislative and Administrative Implementation of International Human Rights Norms, LawBhoomi.com, 07/03/21
- Reproductive Rights of Women in India: A Struggle for Autonomy and Equality, Legal Services India.com, 10/09/23
- Unveiling the Sperm Donation Enigma: Navigating India's Intricate Regulatory Landscape, Legal Services India.com, 10/06/23

# **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Participated in Workshop on 'Practical Aspects of Indian Evidence Act',
  2020
- Participated in National Seminar 'Gandhi on Duties', 2020
- Constitutional Law Quiz at Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University, New-Delhi, 2020
- Para-legal Volunteer, Delhi State Legal Services Authority, 2019-2022
- Volunteered at the K.K. Luthra Moot Court Competition, 2020

## **POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY**

- Member, Legal-Aid Society, Campus Law Centre, 2019-2022
- Member, National Services Scheme, P.G.DAV College, 2015-2018
- Member, Anant Mathematical Society, P.G.DAV College, 2015-2018
- Volunteered in Various College Fests and Events, 2015-2018
- Tutor for students up to class 8th, 2017-2018

# PERSONAL INFORMATION

Age: 27

# **LANGUAGES**

**Hindi:** First Language

English: C1

Advanced (C1)